The SCOAN Sunday Service
Hallelujah!
Good Morning, Church!
(Good Morning!)
Emmanuel! (God is with us!)
Viewers all over the world, I say "Good Morning" to you.
(Good Morning!)
Morning to your life, [Amen!]
to your business, [Amen!]
your career, [Amen!]
your family [Amen!]
Good Morning!
(Good Morning!)
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Hallelujah!
The Lord asked me to come to your midst.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
And also to share with you some of the present challenges.
They are everywhere; it is everywhere!
Where can we go from these challenges?
(Nowhere!)
I can't hear you
It is epidemic.
I don't know where you can go from these challenges.
Even if you go underground, the challenges are there.
If you decided to go inside the sea, you will find challenges there.
Air? Oh my God! You will see clouds covering you.
Everywhere are challenges.
You choose to go inside the bush; you will see challenges there.
I want to say, it is the season; the season of challenges.
How do these challenges relate to our Christian life?
Your challenges could be this or that; you know the kind of challenges you have.
There is no one without challenges.
Yes, I mean there is no one without limitations.
Okay? So everyone, everyone, everyone, just everyone.
It is impossible to live without challenges.
Tell your neighbour.
(It is impossible to live without challenges.)
I can't hear you
It is impossible to live without challenges.
Where can you go from these?
So, how do these challenges relate to your Christian life?
Does it mean you are not a Christian? Or what does this mean? Having challenges?
The type of challenges you have is not the type of challenges I have.
The area you have challenges is not the area I have mine.
When we talk of challenges, knowledge is not the key; obedience is.
When we talk of what?
(Challenges)
Knowledge is not the key - because you apply knowledge.
That cannot work.
Knowledge is not the key, but obedience is.
Challenges determine where you are spiritually.
Viewers, are you there?
Yes, listen to me: Challenges determine where you are spiritually.
This is why knowledge is not the key; obedience is.
What do I mean?
Challenges reveal the true condition of man's heart.
When you see someone who is very quiet, gentle - this reminds me of one of my evangelists.
When he first came to join us, people said, "This man is very quiet".
Indeed, he was very quiet and smiley.
People said, "Oh, he is nice". Everybody wanted to rally around him.
I said, "Wow! No, it is too early".
Let's pose challenges and see whether he will remain the same.
Okay, go and accuse him wrongly - just any accusation.
"Come on! You stole my money! You stole my money!"
"You mean I stole your money? What are you saying?"
"I said you stole my money! I saw you! I am going to report you to the man of God!"
The two of them rushed to my office, and I knew what they were talking about because we started it.
I said, "Okay, okay, you people should come".
The gentleman was just coming; immediately his face changed.
A gentleman that they said he's too gentle, very nice, changed!
He became wild and said to me, "I swear in the name of Jesus!"
I said, "No, don't swear! Don't use the name of Jesus to swear.
But they say you are very quiet; you are very nice".
"Aaah no, no! I'm nice but I can't just allow somebody to lie against me. This is stupid!
You lady - you are an idiot!"
I said, "Can you see someone you said is very quiet and gentle?"
The SCOAN Sunday Service
I said to them, "Look, there's nothing like you have stolen money.
Everyone says that you are very quiet and gentle and you are a 'messiah' and I said to them
they should pose a challenge to you and see whether you remain a 'messiah'.
Can you see now you are not gentle? You are pretending!"
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Challenges determine where you are spiritually, reveal the true condition of a man's heart.
So let me take you to the book of Hebrews 5.
I will take my reading from verse 1 and later we can go to the proof text.
"Every high priest is selected from among the people and is appointed to represent the people in matters
related to God, to offer gifts and sacrifices for sins.
He is able to deal gently with those who are ignorant and are going astray,
since he himself is subject to weakness.
This is why he has to offer sacrifices for his own sins, as well as for the sins of the people."
Lets take you to verse 7 and 8.
"During the days of Jesus’ life on earth, he offered up prayers and petitions with fervent cries and tears
to the one who could save him from death, the one who could save him from death
with crying and what? Tears.
Jesus was heard because of his reverent submission.
Verse 8
Son though he was, he learned obedience from what he suffered."
Though Jesus was a Son of God, He learned obedience by the things He suffered.
He went through agony, anguish and physical pain.
The Bible says "reverent submission".
That is, He submitted to the revealing Word of God.
Jesus submitted to the revealing Word of God.
This means spiritual growth is a function of obedience to the will of God.
And this will take us to the title: KNOWLEDGE IS NOT THE KEY, OBEDIENCE IS
In 1 Peter 4:1, Jesus suffered for us in the flesh.
He suffered for us in the flesh.
If Jesus suffered for us in the flesh, we should arm ourselves with the same manner,
the same attitude, the same mind.
The Bible says, "For he who has suffered in the flesh has ceased from sin".
He who has suffered from the flesh has ceased from what? (Sin) From sin.
That is, stopped sinning.
Jesus learned obedience by the things He suffered.
We learn obedience by the difficult challenges we face today.
Tell your neighbour, "Learn obedience by the difficulty you face today".
I can't hear you.
[Learn obedience by the difficulty you face today.]
What are the difficulties you are facing - those challenges?
Our situations are tests to mature us.
Tell your neighbour, "My situations are tests to mature me".
I can't hear you.
[My situations are tests to mature me.]
My challenges are tests to mature me.
What are your challenges? What is your situation?
That is a question you need to ask yourself.
What are your challenges? What is your situation as a Christian?
They are tests to mature you.
Whatever situations you are facing, don't allow them to control you.
When your situation controls you, you will lose all sense of reasoning.
This is what is happening to you today.
Everyone that is better than you - they are criminals, they are corrupt people, they are thieves.
When you don't have a vehicle and you are on your way and you see a posh car - they are criminals,
they are the ones carrying our money!
Because we have lost sense of what? Reasoning.
When poverty comes and you allow poverty to control you, hardship to control you,
those who are better than you in terms of money, wealth - they are your enemy.
When you allow your depression to control you, those who are happy - they are your enemy.
When you allow your sickness to control you, those who are not sick - they are your enemy.
When they laugh, you feel irritated.
And when you are not sick and you are healthy, if you allow your good health to control you as well,
those who are sick - you will think as a result of their sin comes sickness.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
2 Timothy 3:7 says, we are "always learning but never able to come to the knowledge of the truth".
Sin easily hides where there is no heat of trial and temptation.
Where there is no heat of challenges, sin easily hides.
Just as impurity hides in gold until it goes into processing.
You know gold.
The impurity on that gold must be removed before it becomes gold.
So in the same way, sin, iniquity, easily hides where there is no heat of challenges, trial, temptation, trouble.
In time of prosperity and success, you will see the evil one rejoicing and rejoicing.
But when the heat of trials and temptations comes, their evil action surfaces.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
No matter how much you master the Scripture...
The Bible - which many of us are using today as a cover up.
We hide under the knowledge of the Bible to deceive the world that you are a Christian,
you are a Bishop, you are a Prophet, you are Archbishop - whatever name you call yourself.
We are hiding under the knowledge of the Bible.
And knowledge is not the key; obedience is
No matter how much you master the Scripture,
without true obedience to what you read, you still wear spiritual diapers.
We continue to learn and come to church from far and wide
to hear this message of God, and many of us live with Emmanuel TV.
We live with what?
(Emmanuel TV)
Yes. That is, as I am talking now, some of us turn it on in our bedroom.
Our children put it on all the time
We live with it.
Yet, we never mature because of disobedience.
Knowledge is not the key; obedience is.
Tell your neighbour.
We continue learning, coming to church from far and wide, to hear the message of the Gospel,
yet we never mature because of disobedience.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Maturity is all about Christ.
When you are not mature, you are ignorant and ignorance is a sin.
When you are not mature, you react intellectually to the the things of God.
You react by what you see and you think it is godly way to do that.
You react by what you hear.
"Eeeh, eeh, you said this to me!?"
"You mean? My wife? My wife did this? You saw my wife there?"
"Yes, I saw your wife there!"
And you would not know that they want to scatter your marriage!
It is easy to destroy those who are not mature. If you are not mature, you are just food to satan.
Any time they see you happy, they will go into a corner and make a phone call to you.
"This man is happy; let me give him unhappiness!"
They now will give you phone call.
"Hello?"
"Yes, you see, I saw your wife. The place I saw your wife is very, very bad."
"I am telling you; you know it is bad."
"Ehn ehn, where?"
"This place, that place."
"Aaaah, thank you, thank you, thank you, thank you."
You drop the phone and you say, [Crying] "I loved this woman! I loved her!
I don't know why she would behave like this to me!" You want to commit suicide.
Those who have committed suicide - 50% of them -
they act ignorantly -
what they hear, what they see, what their circumstances look like.
So, these are the weapons against immature Christians.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Take note of this word. Now take it and work on it.
Your challenges determine where you are spiritually.
Your challenges could be sickness, poverty, hardship, insult, temptation - just name them.
Trials and temptations determine where we are spiritually.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
How you react when you are under pressure and how you react when you are under those challenges...
You will see the way you react is how the real you reacts.
It's how the real you reacts. Say, "How I react".
How I react under pressure - I mean, under challenges - I mean, under your problem...
I don't know the condition you are in - maybe hardship, sickness, debt or hardship.
How you react is how the real you reacts.
And the real you is the one serving God, not you.
You are here today because you have transport to come to the church or you are able to fuel your car.
Assume, you have no money to fuel your car, you will likely send your children to church and sit at home
because you do not want to be shamed by people around you.
You have forgotten that the same God that gave you the vehicle,
that gave you the car when you were nobody before
and the Lord now gave you the vehicle - you are now using the same vehicle against Him!
By looking at the way people dance, you will know who is this man!
Whether he is coming to give testimony or he is coming with trouble.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
You see some dances; they will do like this.
While some dance, they will say, "Hallelujah, hallelujah".
You know that satan has hit him.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Trials and temptations determine where you are spiritually.
How you react under pressure, how you react under your situation, is how the real you reacts.
PRAYER TIME
Let me believe today's message blessed your soul. Knowledge is not the key; obedience is.
You just need to take your time. Meditate on it.
Meditation brings revelation.
Where there is no vision, people perish.
My dear viewers, let us pray.
Whatever medium you are using to view us, Jesus knows.
Dear viewers all over the world, the devil wants us to curse Jesus while under our situation.
The devil wants us to curse Jesus while under pain, affliction, poverty.
Our situations are tests to mature us.
Don't allow any situation to control you.
Don't allow any situation to mislead you or overwhelm you.
Stay and cope with hard and good moments.
Viewers, listen. Stay and cope with hard and good moments.
A person can be sick in body and yet be a Christian, a friend of God, and a favorite of Jesus.
Don't measure your Christian life by your situation.
Don't allow your situation to mislead you.
I want to pray with you.
Viewers all over the world, whatever situation you are in, in the name of Jesus, I release you!
Be released in the name of Jesus!
Whatever you are passing through right now, be released in the name of Jesus!
Whatever situation you are going through in your life, be released in the name of Jesus!
You situation, I say, "Go! Leave my people, leave their business, leave their career, in the name of Jesus!"
I can see you being released.
Where there is no vision, people perish.
I can hear breakthrough! Breakthrough in your way, health, career, destiny!
Breakthrough, breakthrough, breakthrough, breakthrough, in the name of Jesus!
Thank You, Jesus. Thank You, Jesus, for their breakthrough.
Thank You, Jesus, for their breakthrough, in Jesus Christ's name!
Viewers all over the world, I will know before you that you are free.
I say to you, you are free in the name of Jesus!
I can see you being set free.
Whatever situation in your health, any area of your organs that is not functioning,
be it your kidneys, liver, blood, fluid, or bones, be restored, in the name of Jesus!
Be restored in the name of Jesus!
You are restored!
I can see you being restored!
It's a vision - I can see you being restored, in the name of Jesus!
Thank You, Jesus!
Those of you that are under the influence of my voice,
you believe Jesus is Lord, Healer, Deliverer, Saviour.
I say to you, this is your testimony - testimony of your health!
This is your testimony - testimony of your finances!
This is your testimony - testimony of your breakthrough!
This is your testimony - testimony of your restoration!
Yes, I can hear breakthrough once again.
Breakthrough! Breakthrough! Breakthrough! Thank You, Jesus!
I rejoice with you, in Jesus Christ's name.
Amen! Amen! Amen!